[Music]
w
hello and welcome back to the ask abijit
Show episode 206 I hope everybody is
doing great and thank you so much for
being on this live stream and for all
the questions that you have asked and
are going to ask today's episode is
going to be more about questions that I
will take from the comments questions
that you've asked in the comments I'll
take a bunch of those and then if there
is time I'll take more questions from
the live chat so before we get into the
questions as always let me see who all
is there I can see Vladimir Chava Mr
macius moit Pand Satish Chan cop J jwal
minini good evening aradya andan an
prash Jam Patel
hello pan Kumar Singh online y bro Dre
guman good morning from from Mumbai
you're from Montreal good shat shat
arpit aaral jit rakit Mishra bju Ashish
Krishna Matrix artillery chavda Manan
Chopra ragir solanki subba Redi wuru
Divine in nature Atul bat Rahul Tade
niharika Gupta Illuminati hello RV WV
1313 uh
kava from East Pakistan formerly
Bangladesh hello I'm good to good to
hear from you Surendra Gupta manjit
Kumar Akil Nali Shar ravindra Chri C
jwal prti PA Itachi uni rajat Chopra
namaskaram ad R shagun Chopra hello from
akashwani
Sunil Kumar laxo LAX bug s subra chatur
geopolitical du good evening good day
pan Kumar Singh Joan Patel Mohit Pand
laet other are threat Ripper rul KRA
Matrix prab pulkit BoJack
Horseman uh and so many other people
goami alok but artillery chavda Sam X
suit statement namaskar subam de vs
Ganesh heg shuti Jo in pragati arush and
everybody else okay I'm going to end
stop that now and start taking
questions so what questions do we have
let us begin with questions
comments this is a comment by thees
question by thees I do not smoke or do
anything harmful I'm 31 I developed a
zero level level zero lung cancer is it
related to genes or pollution I'm better
after surgery how can people avoid this
this is terrible news and I'm I'm I hope
you're doing much better after the
surgery I'm very sorry to hear about
this uh I'm glad that it was caught
early and hopefully uh it won't cause
any problems going forward if it's
caught early and the right measures are
taken surgery Etc then generally you
should be fine so uh terrible to hear
this I hope you're doing very well and I
I and I'm sure there are lots of people
who come across this un these unexpected
diagnosis there seems to be an upsurging
cancers Etc especially among youngsters
and among people who have never done any
of these things like smoking or whatever
it is and yet you you get these things
what is the re reason for that right
that's the question um is it related to
genes or pollution so I think that uh
more than genes it may have something to
do with increasing increased levels of
pollution that we have we are
experiencing these days in the world we
have microplastics in everything we can
consum in water in in all the foods that
we consume the water that we drink is is
contaminated with God knows how many
chemicals and whatnot vegetables and
other other food products are
contaminated with pesticides there are
GMOs genetically modified organisms and
there's a lot more there there there are
all these issues today that we do not
have few decades earlier and then
there's also the there's also
hidden problems that we may not be aware
of there are certain parts regions in
the world where there
is where where radon
gas escapes you know in small quantities
from the ground and radon gas is a
radioactive gas it's a noble gas but
it's radioactive and that if you inhale
could uh perhaps uh you know could
definitely increase the possibility that
people may get lung cancer and other
cancers then there is exposure to to
asbestos toxins like that you know uh in
the past a few decades ago asbestos was
not known to be a causative factor in in
lung cancer misoa Etc so and and ASP
used to be used for roofing in in
buildings and whatnot and insulation Etc
so there are so many of these factors
that most people are not aware of of in
the west at least they they look for you
know they they do whenever a building is
being constructed they look for uh
possible sources of radon gas
contamination Etc in India no one is
even aware of this so there are so many
factors that could cause this and uh
somebody who gets this may wonder what
on Earth happened I have never smoked I
have never engaged in any risky activity
and yet I got this particular form of
cancer well there are there could be so
many caus
so yeah one has to be careful you have
to take care of your health you have to
get yourself checked if if you feel
something is aiss even slightly and I'm
so glad they just that you discovered
this at a very early stage and you got
the Sur required surgery um going
forward I would highly recommend that
you get yourself tested I'm sure the
doctors would have told you that you
need to get yourself tested once every 6
months or so or whatever the frequency
is whether it's 3 months 6 months one
year whatever it is I think the the the
higher the frequency the better
especially in the initial few years uh
so yeah and and I suppose that this
would have to continue for the rest of
your life but I think it's a small price
to pay for a for a healthy long and
healthy life so uh so yeah that's very
surprising but uh I'm glad it was it was
caught early and it was addressed and uh
thank you for sharing this and I wish
you nothing but a very long and healthy
and disease free life all
right Itachi uch says feeling
disheartened by the world's cruelty I've
lost sight of my life's purpose while
preparing for the upsc and without any
family I feel isolated and uncertain
what do I do what should I do I'm 23 uh
you're speaking you know you speaking on
behalf of millions of youngsters in this
country there are so many young men and
and women young boys and girls who go
through exactly the same thing and I I
suppose almost everybody at some stage
in their life especially when you're
trans transitioning from adolescence to
adulthood or somewhere before after I
think I suppose almost everybody at some
point in life they they feel this way so
what should you do about this that's the
question see generally you feel this you
get this feeling this sense of futility
sense of being disheartened Etc when you
realize the true begin to see the true
nature of the world which is very
competitive very Cutthroat very
unforgiving uh when you go through
childhood especially if you have
reasonably good parents and family then
you live a reasonably sheltered life I
mean parents naturally will ensure that
uh you're not exposed to Too Much
hardship and too much of the cruelty
that uh can be part of life so you go
through that and the education system
doesn't definitely does not prepare you
for what to expect after you are done
studying so once you're done with all
that and you come out into the world
you're no longer a student and you are
looking for a career and that's when you
discover how competitive the world is
and there are the resources are scarce
and the competition is very very intense
there are lots of people who are all
competing for the for very a very small
number of whatever it is seats or jobs
or whatever resources whatever and yeah
you you find yourself lost essentially
and you feel that the world is really
cruel I mean childhood was so nice and
why is the world so evil so cruel and
all so I think almost everybody at some
stage of their life goes through this
you feel perhaps depressed perhaps uh
lost perhaps disillusioned disheartened
Etc uh so what do you do about this what
do you do about this is the question
right so first of all we you have to
understand that the world has always
been this way it's always been this way
the world hasn't changed off late it's
not like in the past 5 10 20 years the
world has become an inherently more
cruel place it's not the world has
always been this way it's just that you
are now beginning to realize that what
it is really like because you're no
longer a student you're no longer
shelter
you have your own you have to take care
of yourself Etc so you're beginning to
see it now so the world has always been
this way that's the first thing you have
to understand the second thing you to
understand is that you can deal with
this you
can uh overcome whatever obstacles you
are faced with look it's like this you
are the result of millions not millions
billions of years of evolution evolution
is about the survival of the
fittest way more organisms and see look
if you go back in history we all have
thousands hundreds of thousands of
ancestors if you talk about the time
span of homo sapiens and before that we
have prehuman ancestors and so on so
each one of your ancestors was able to
pass on their genetic
material successfully they were able to
successfully compete and Thrive and
that's why you exist
so the genetic material of those who
fail in the race of Life of survival of
the fittest it doesn't get passed on so
you have the material the genetic
material of thousands hundreds of
thousands of generations of winners okay
so you have it in you so you should not
doubt your ability your capability to
survive and not only survive but to win
and thrive
so that should hopefully give you a
little bit of uh confidence now the
thing is this you may feel like you've
lost sight of what was your purpose in
life that is very common especially when
you're young and you thrust into the
into the uh into the ocean like like the
Spartans used to throw their kids into
the ocean and sink or swim that sort of
thing so what should you do well ideally
you need to take some time off to
reconnect with who you are and what your
as
aspirations in life are you need to
spend some time alone when you're just
running running running when you're just
studying studying every day when you
simply don't have time to be alone with
yourself then you simply don't feel you
you get the feeling that you uh you've
lost connection with who you are and
that's why it feels like you've lost
sight of your life's purpose so maybe
you need to take a couple of days off
put away your textbooks put away your
study material go somewhere ideally go
to a national park a forest or something
spend a few hours walking alone
observing nature observing the
butterflies observing the the the the
leopards eating the
deers whatever it is be alone in nature
okay walk take a long long walk several
hours and then automatically you will
reconnect with who you are there is
nothing more beneficial for a human
being than a long walk in in nature now
maybe you don't have access to a
national park or a forest or something
then find some other way go to the
seashore or go somewhere where you have
few people around you when you have a
million people talking in your ears you
simply you know it's it's a huge problem
you need to you every human being needs
uh regular periods of solitude and and
reflection so I think you need to take a
couple of days off maybe two or three
days off two three days you don't study
won't make any big difference so uh do
that reconnect with who you are you will
discover you will ReDiscover what you
are here for and what your aspirations
are and your aspirations are your
purpose especially at the age of 23 so
that's what you should do the main thing
is be positive be confident know that
you are you are the descendant of so
many lineages of people who have
succeeded that's why you here and you
have the genetic ingredients and all
that required to succeed in life uh it's
always good to do connect with family
and all but sometimes when you study
when you student student or whatever you
have to move away from family so you
have to find the Reserves of strength
from within yourself and I'm I assure
you that you have that okay so yeah that
that's part of life that's part of
growing up you come face to face with
the true nature of the world the Maya
the illusion the wheel of Maya
disappears and then you see what the
world really is then I assure you it's
not all cruel it's not all evil there's
a lot of good in the world too but you
have to discover that you to strive to
discover it and that and essentially
like so so many of our ancients
said life is kind of a struggle and the
struggle is what gives you meaning gives
your life meaning so overall you got to
enjoy the struggle you got to win you
you to find ways to win and enjoy
winning and you go forward with that so
that's that's what I would suggest you
do take some time off reconnect with
yourself and you will find what it is
that you're missing I wish you the best
sir
okay grave Walker 34 says Prime Minister
Modi gave a message to the superpower in
his speech that he delivered on the 15th
of August what's my take on it what is
this message was a long speech right so
let's let's uh try and see what this
message was that the Prime Minister
delivered to the superpower like you say
so here it is here is that particular
segment or excerpt of that
speech here's what it says
friends and he's addressing us the
citizens of India friends we are facing
countless challenges both internal as
well as external challenges as we are
going to become stronger as our status
Rises challenges are going to multiply
external challenges are going to rise
disproportionately I am well aware of
that however I want to tell other great
Powers our prosperity will not create
problems for you back when we were prous
we did not start wars we follow the
teachings of Lord Buddha well I'm
surprised it's Lord Buddha this time not
Mr Gandhi but anyway uh we follow the
teachings of Lord Buddha we don't
believe in Wars so the world should not
be worried about India's growth I want
to assure the world you should trust in
India's Traditions India's history of
thousands of years do not think we are
going to be a problem for you do not
scheme against us to make our path to
growth more difficult but still I want
to tell the people of the country we
will overcome the challenges all the
challenges thrown at us we will not stop
we will not Tire we are determined to
fulfill the dreams of 1.4 billion
Indians we will win over all ill
intentioned ill-intentioned people with
our good intentions so the Prime
Minister says very clearly that external
challenges are going to rise
disproportionately now what which are
these external challenges it's clear
that and he's talking about the great
powers and superpowers isn't he so
obviously he's talking about the United
States the illusion is very very clear
there is no doubt about what he is
talking about he's talking about the
United States and he's talking about the
fact that as India status is
rising as as India becomes stronger
these external challenges are going to
multiply and rise disproportionately and
it's already happening we know that we
know that so he's assuring he's sending
a message to the US that we back when we
were prosperous we did not start wars
and now he's usually Mr Modi refers to
Mr Gandhi but this time he's referring
to Mr to to to goam Buddha Lord
Buddha because probably Lord Buddha is a
more powerful symbol of non-violence and
non-aggression so Mr Modi is trying to
reassure the United States that we are
not going to create problems for you and
we not going to start wars well yeah so
he's sending a message to the people of
India that yes we are facing this
problem the Americans are trying to
meddle everywhere they're trying to
hamper our rise they're trying to
whatever they are doing I have explained
in great detail so many times what the
Americans are trying to do with us with
India they're trying to cut off India's
access to the rest of the world and try
to trying to meddle in India's Internal
Affairs create all kinds of fissures and
divisions within the country exploit
those divisions and just slow India's
growth down and reduce India to
mediocrity that's the overall objective
that the Americans have the Americans
have a very fundamental approach and
envisioned future for the world they
want either a monopolar unipolar world
or a bipolar world that is the US and
China they don't even want Russia in the
picture Okay so the Americans want a
monopolar unipolar or bipolar World
India wants a multipolar world it's a
fundamental difference in the envisaged
future of the world what we want and
what they want it's a fundamental
difference it is irreconcilable do you
understand the US and India have
irreconcilable bable
differences the Americans are way
powerful than us so they can do whatever
they want essentially and that's the
challenge that India faces so Mr Modi
without naming them has sent a message
to them he has also sent a message to in
the citizens of India that we are in for
a tough
time it is what it is so that's my take
on it the the the illusion it's very
clear who is's referring to he's not
referring to China he he talks about
multiple Powers right right uh uh what
what what's it say uh I want to tell
other great Powers well essentially he's
he's talking about the US not really
China here
so it's very clear Mr Modi
uh understands that we are in for a
tough time we're going to have lots of
challenges growing challenges mounting
challenges that are going to be thrown
at us the Americans are going to
interfere in India's Internal Affairs in
a multitude of
ways they have so many assets within
India I assure you of
that they're going to leverage all those
assets they're going to bring all those
assets into play there are assets
without India there are assets within
India much more so India is going to be
in for a tough time that's for sure so
yeah that's the message that Prime
Minister Modi has given and he has said
he has given this message of uh of
resilience that no matter what happens
we're going to keep on working and
striving to to keep on the on on the
path that we are destined to be on
that's
one Sona k k Sonia condal sorry says
this year the Deep state has activated
all its anti-india Assets in full force
the prime minister's third term is going
to be the deciding factor for the future
of Barat do you agree I do agree now let
me uh show you something okay I'm going
to put something on the screen uh if
it's a video I had put up quite a while
ago okay uh let's go to the screen here
we
are
and let's let's go down the this is my
YouTube channel these are the videos
that I put out and we're talking about
um where is that it's it's quite a while
ago it was in the beginning of 2023 that
I put this video out
and I'm sure I can play it over here
because there's no going to be no
copyright strike it's it's my own video
I want copyright strike
myself uh but where is this one second
give me a second we're talking about a
year
ago it's been quite a while since I put
this out I think it was part of the
Indian interest
podcast give me a second I'm going to
dig it out
so I had spoken about this this one here
this
video and I want play it right now but
the topic the title is the West's pre
2024 anti-india propaganda has begun and
I put this out on January
2023 I would urge you all I would
encourage you all to watch this video or
to rewatch this video okay in which I
have spoken about the what what the
West's game plan is going to be like and
let me assure you what you seeing today
is exactly what I had spoken about in
January
2023 so uh watch the video I'll put out
a community post also with with the link
for the video after this live stream is
over check it out and what's happening
today is exactly what I had laid laid
out in detail in that particular video
so yes the the Deep state or whatever
you want to call it all it's an
anti-india assets outside of India
within India have been activated in full
force what they did in Bangladesh in the
years in in the years the before the
coup happened the exact same Playbook is
being followed in India right now so it
looks like their objective is eventually
to have that sort of regime change in
India as well okay and yeah there are so
many assets they can they can bring into
play
Indian assets which belong to them uh so
yes the prime ministers prime minister
modi's thirdd term is going to be
extremely challenging for him for the
country for his for the government and
it probably is going to be the deciding
factor for the future of Barat if they
can bring this regime the prime
minister's government down the Americans
but if they can engineer a regime change
then it's essentially very difficult
days ahead for India okay so yeah we are
in like I say like I keep saying for a
tough time
the Prime Minister and his party they
don't have a full majority they have
what 240 seats in Parliament the halfway
mark is 272
273 so yeah big
challenge they should have got the
majority they didn't do it so now yeah
it it gives The Outsiders an
opening and they will they are Past
Masters at exploiting openings so it's
going to be tough days ahead for
India okay Sun Moon 0877
says why are the US desperately trying
to wipe Hinduism out in Bangladesh and
Pakistan why do they prefer monotheistic
religions or polytheistic religions what
obstacles do they see in Hinduism to
proceed with their plan to create a
nation okay yeah so first of all why is
the US trying to wipe out Hinduism and
Bangladesh and Pakistan well there is
no evidence the US is behind it there's
always a tremendous amount of plausible
deniability we have nothing to do with
this we have nothing to do with this
this was a students
protest it was a students protest and
the Army turned out to be such such a
nice thing Pro Democratic they supported
the students protest and they had they
made shik leave and now the new
government has taken over it's a it's a
proper transition of power and we we
support it we welcome it and and and the
media will black out the entire you know
large scale targeting of Hindus that's
happening as we speak right now in
Bangladesh they'll completely black it
out blank it out they'll not report it
at all so so then people can say what
what's happening there's nothing in the
media nothing in the news where is toy
evidence but the media will stay away
from it they will not show show record
this they will not run any stories about
this so then we will have no evidence
but the evidence is coming out on social
media all the videos of what's happening
the the the targeting of Hindus in a
variety of ways okay I'll not say
anything beyond that that's happening so
and again again the Americans will say
if there is some violence happening we
condemn it and we have nothing to do
with it obviously they still have
plausible deniability now they had that
they tried that in 1971 as well we have
nothing to do with it but they were
behind the genocide they were supporting
the Pakistani army genocide in East
Pakistan the Americans andan and their
own uh Ambassador wrote about this read
the book The Blood telegram the
Americans knew what was happening and
they supported that so now the question
is
why are they let's say okay with the
targeting of Hindus in East Pakistan
which is which is the former Bangladesh
why are they okay with it and why are
they if they're okay with it it means
they want it right why do they want
it so understand this as long as there
is a sizable Hindu population in
Bangladesh or east Pakistan there's
going to be Indian influence there there
is going to be Indian influence in
Bangladesh or east Pakistan as long as
there is a sizable Hindu population
there there is zero almost zero Indian
influence in Pakistan today because the
population of Hindus has has almost
disappeared right what 2% less than 2% I
don't know what the Hindu population of
Pakistan
is so that's why because there are
almost no Hindus left there that's why
India has almost no influence there in
Pakistan and the same goes about
Afghanistan we have a good RA with the
Taliban that's a different story but if
we had let's say five % Hindus
still existing in Afghanistan then we
would have some influence there right
let's say Afghanistan was still let's
say 10% Hindu we would have influence in
Afghanistan today we have nothing I mean
I think there's zero Hindus left in
Afghanistan now 100 years ago there was
a sizable Hindu population a thousand
years ago everybody was Hindu so that's
how we have receded our civilizational
footprint has receded so if the Hindus
are wiped out in East Pakistan in
Bangladesh then India's influence
decreases to zero that's fantastic for
the Puppet Master who's behind the
regime change behind the coup the US so
that's why they want to wipe out
Hinduism they so that's number one
number two the question is why do they
prefer monotheistic religions or
polytheistic religions monotheistic
religions are easy to
control it's very easy to control the
entire structure religious structure is
is is a military style structure it's a
command and control structure
okay so and and monotheistic religions
are all about obedience and Blind Faith
polytheistic religions are about
arguments and not agreeing with with
each other it's more
democratic and you will see that
monotheistic people who follow
monotheistic religions are very well
organized and un unified
United and as you know very well people
who follow polytheistic religions have a
diversity and pl plurality of opinions
and paths and World Views and ways of
life and the Hindus are the best example
of
that they simply cannot unite Hindus no
matter where they are they simply can't
unite they simply can't
organize they simply can't present a
unified front never so who wants to deal
with such people you want to deal with
people a bunch of people who are so who
are incredibly easy to
control right so you if you if you're a
shefer
you will prefer
sheep right or or let's say a pack of
wolves for example a pack of wolves also
canot can be controlled it also has a
command and control structure a pack of
wolves but how about a bunch of cats can
you control can you her a bunch of cats
impossible so polytheistic people are
like a bunch of cats they simply have
their own Divergent paths you simply
cannot hurt them together it is just
beyond the nature it's outside of the
nature so the US is an Empire an Empire
is all about power and power is about
command and
control and that's why they prefer to
deal with monotheistic religions because
they're easy to command and control
polytheist my goodness who will Who
what's what a headache it is for them
right um so the the that's the thing so
that's the problem with
Hinduism that it simply doesn't unite
the people aren't United and that's why
the Americans the Americans prefer
dictatorships because that's once again
very simplified command and control
structure democracies are a pain they
profess to spread democracy in the world
and and support democracy encourage
democracy but they actually support
authoritarian regimes so their words and
actions don't match never
match but whatever regime they support
they claim it's Democratic like zilinski
zilinski is a dictator okay according to
the Constitution of Ukraine he should
have been out of power he should have
been there should have been in an
election in Ukraine in what in April May
June somewhere around that time that
time is long past gone zilinski is in
power unconstitutionally
undemocratically according to the
Constitution of Ukraine he's a
dictator then the Americans support him
they have propped up his regime so there
you have it so yeah I hope that answers
your questions
next question aders Narayan R says what
must the Modi government do to protect
Hindus from Bangladesh recently many
people on the India Bangladesh border
have claimed that the that they are
Hindus but the BSF the border security
Force the Indian border security Force
are not letting them enter India
according to Indian government there are
very few women and children among them
which is strange I agree it's strange
and practically we cannot give shelter
to one CR Hindus in India now
right Bangladesh has a very large
population overall total in in total and
I don't know about 7% of of them are
Hindus which is a very large population
at least 10 million right uh so yeah how
can we bring in 10 million people into
India it will overburden our our our
economy or infrastructure our our state
machinery and whatnot right so the
question then is what and and lots of
people are are criticizing the the Modi
government for not allowing Hindus to
cross over into the Bangladeshi Hindus
to cross over into
India so the question is what should the
Modi government do should we open the
border and allow the Hindus to cross
over and then there's the risk of
non-hindus and and anti-india not about
non-hindus but about anti-india Elements
Crossing over into India in the guise of
Hindus right that that's that's always a
risk we've had this problem with
Bangladesh for a very long time so what
should the Modi government do
uh and lots of people are saying okay
very prominent voices on social media
are saying that India needs to allow
these Bangladeshi Hindus to enter India
so that they can have safe refuge in
India what's my view on this my view on
this is rather different I suppose it
may be an unpopular view my view is that
we should not allow the Bangladeshi
Hindus to enter India
but but we support them we give them
funds we give them everything they need
to carve out a Hindu region in
Bangladesh okay so let's take a look at
the map see how long are you going to
keep running that's the question how
long will Hindus keep running we run
away from Afghanistan we run away from
Pakistan we run away from Central Asia a
long long time ago we ran away from sang
when the UR massacred Hindus we have run
away from from various parts of the
world we keep running running running
like cowards got to stand and fight for
what's yours okay so here's what I would
say let's take a look at the
map okay here's the map on the screen
you have Bangladesh here so now the
India the government of India should
provide every possible assistance to
Hindus in Bangladesh to carve
out a Hindu Nation out of Bangladesh the
Americans are trying to create an
artificial cookie Nation right
artificial Christian Nation out of parts
of Burma Bangladesh and Manipur and
mizoram right now the India Bangladesh
border is porous it's an open border and
we have always been on the receiving end
of the porosity of this border whether
is the Bangladesh border or the Pakistan
border we have always been at the
receiving end now let us demonstrate to
the world that a poorest border works
both ways we can also do things across
the border so we need to provide every
every possible assistance of the
Bangladeshi Hindus so that they can
organize themselves they can arm
themselves they can ensure that nobody
can Target them and they can carve out
an independent Hindu Nation out of let's
say Western
Bangladesh that's what India needs to do
we should tell the our Hindu brothers
and sisters in Bangladesh that they need
to stand and fight and we will stand
with them and we will provide them every
help they need but we will not uh allow
them to escape and run into India stand
and fight and we'll give you everything
you need that's what the Modi government
would do
at some point in time we going to give
it back we have been running away long
enough do you agree my viewers do you
agree let me let me see the let me see
the
comments
uh okay I'm not sure if
uh so basically that that's that's my
view we need
to we need to ensure that a Hindu is
created out of
Bangladesh and it's not about abandoning
the Hindus of Bangladesh it's about
giving them everything they need to
fight back and and fight for what is
theirs that is their land they are in
they are in their own land the land of
their ancestors the land that lived in
for thousands of years don't give it up
stand and fight and the government of
India I urge them to support the Hindus
of Bangladesh in this manner not by by
by
uh helping them run away but by helping
them stand stand and fight Malik said
says will that not be open challenge to
the US yeah but do it in a way that
there is plausible deniability just the
way the Americans do it the Americans
supported Pakistani terrorism in India
they funded and financed Pakistani
terrorism in India for
decades and they always said that we
have plausible deniability there is no
evidence that we are supporting and we
are simply blah blah blah whatever do
the same thing do the same thing you
want to play this game we will also play
the game I know it's it's dangerous but
you you have to take a stand at some
point in time the Americans are trying
to break your nation they're trying to
break the Far East of India they're
trying to create a artificial cookie
land out of Manipur and mizoram and
whatnot and they are trying to create
divisions in the country you got to
fight back at some point in in in in
your life so I think that's what the
government of India needs to do that's
my perspective and this has nothing to
do with religious conflict Hindu versus
Muslim or whatever this is just about
what should be done that's
it okay Lipton bua says I'm a Buddhist
and mag tribe okay my grandparents were
from
Chittagong Chittagong was dominated by
Buddhists and Hindus my grandparents
wanted to be part of bat how did chagang
become a part of East pakist pistan
despite being
non-muslim okay great question once
again we go to the
map so here is the map of the
subcontinent more or less now we go to
the eastern
part Bangladesh and the eastern part of
Bangladesh the southeast of Bangladesh
is the chattogram region Chong Cox Bazar
Etc and this region overall see
Bangladesh which is East bangal
is definitely a Muslim majority region
and the partition of India the partition
of Barat was done by outside forces by
the British on the basis of religion and
there was this guy called SEL Radcliffe
who arbitrarily drew a line called the
redcliff line which became the border
between India and this new artificial
nation of Pakistan okay so serial
Radcliffe drew the line in the way you
see it on the map right now
and if this entire exercise was based on
religion then chatam chagang this entire
Chittagong Hill tract region should have
been part of bat it should have been
part of India even places like sth Etc
should have been part of India they
should not have been part of Bangladesh
even rangpur Etc these region Raj Shahi
Etc should have been part of India but
the British
artificially made all of these regions
part of East Pakistan why did they do
that so pakist East Pakistan West
Pakistan Pakistan overall this
artificial nation was a geopolitical
project and the objective of the project
was to further the British Imperial and
Colonial interests in the region now
I'll not go into the exact details of
what those interests were and all that
but they wanted this nation okay and
they wanted this nation to be self-
sustaining and it should last for a long
time it should be able to sustain itself
so one of the most important things East
Pakistan needed was was large a large
port and chagang or chatram is a very
big Port it's a major port even coxes
Bazar is is a reasonably good port and
there are no other ports of any
significant stature in East Pakistan and
that's why despite Chittagong being a
non-muslim majority region it was
forcibly made part of East Pakistan
because it has the strategically
important
port that's the reason why it was done
and our so-called wonderful magnificent
founding fathers Mr Neu Mr Gandhi Etc
they allowed this to happen they did not
raise their voice they did not put their
foot down and said that this will not
happen if you're doing it on the basis
of religion then chagang should be part
of
India it should have been part of India
so it was done because chagang is a very
important very strategically located
Port it is vital for it was vital for
East Pakistan to have this port and it
also ensured that the Far East of India
was cut off from the Bay of Bengal from
the Indian Ocean so it served multiple
purposes it gave East Pakistan a very
major strategically important port it
also cut off the Far East of India's
access to the Sea it kills two birds
with one stone that's what the British
achieved by making Chong part of East
Pakistan that's the
deal Okay so
that's how it was done and our wonderful
Freedom Fighters founding fathers like
some people call them they allowed this
to happen show me a news report of of Mr
Gandhi Mr Neu Etc putting up a vigorous
protest against
this show me I'll wait next
question okay uh couple of questions
I've had definitely more but I've taken
as representative questions for for this
topic uh murali and sudip Kar Roy ask
first of all will cookie land form in
the next year second can India withstand
cookie terrorism in the Northeast the
Far East or will India succumb to us
tactics what will be India strategy in
the Far East to control us uh breaking
India activities essentially yeah so
let's once again go to the map firstly
will cookie land form in the next year I
think kiland is already in the process
of formation kiland is already in the
process of formation there is a
tremendous Civil War ring in Burma the
Burmese government the Army the Hun is
not in control of more than half the
country it is in control in less than
half the country today and the uh parts
of Burma that that uh that are east of
Manipur nagaland and mizoram they are
essentially more or less Rebel
controlled who are these Rebels cookies
so you already have a defo cookie land
East right East of Manipur mizoram and
parts of
nagaland and also Bangladesh east of of
chagang so you already have a Cil land
which is being formed right now and when
it comes to Manipur for example the
southern half of Manipur is under cookie
occupation it is already under cookie
occupation
okay they are doing deforestation they
are farming they're planting poppies
growing drugs they're killing endangered
animals the Indian government is able to
do nothing nothing right now this is a
fact okay there is this very uh famous
endangered species of deer in Manipur
called the sangai deer okay the sangai
deer it's an endangered animal it is a
protected animal these cookie
infiltrators are shooting and eating
this
animal a highly endangered critically
endangered animal so so the government
of India has kind of right now for for
for now for the time being kind of lost
control of the Southern half of Manipur
churachandpur this this part this region
that was ethnically cleansed of the
Hindus the cookies are ruling the root
over there so there is a big problem
there when it comes to mizoram I will
not speak about mizoram the less I speak
about mizoram the better as of right now
okay so there are big challenges up for
India kiland is already being formed it
will not be an officially recognized
nation in the United Nations it will be
an artificial temporary nation which
will be de facto Sovereign but it will
be de facto controlled by the US okay
Baptist missionaries all over the place
that's what's going to be there now what
will be the source of revenue for kuki
land
well when the mujahedin were fighting
the Soviets in Afghanistan what was
their main Chief source of Revenue poppy
plantations opium plantations
drugs hard drugs and the exact same
thing is happening in cookie land okay
Manipur is overrun by this this drug
mafias there are poy plantations all
over the place so there you have it it's
already happening and when the New Port
comes up the American base in St
Martin's island or whatever it's called
St Martins yeah St Martin's Island then
they will facilitate the drug trade from
here they'll facilitate the export of
these cookie cookie made narcotics all
across the world so that the cookie
government gets the cookie forces they
get a stable source of Revenue already
happening so what can India do about all
this it's already happening it is
already
happening uh so what can India do about
this the first thing India needs to do
and it's going to take time that's why I
keep saying this is going to take time
the first thing India needs to do is to
seal the entire border with Burma fence
it off and you know it sounds very easy
but take a look at the topology of the
terrain here the Topography of the
terrain okay this is Mor TAMU look at
the entire terrain it's Hills and
forests Hills and forests it's Hills and
forests it's incredibly in difficult to
do anything to to fence this region you
see there is there is this artificial
cookie Village here they deforested the
land all over the place you will see
this you'll see this all over the place
uh anyway I'll not go into that but the
point is India needs to first of all
seal off the Border fence the entire
border India needs to increase its
military presence in the region and I'm
not talking about paramilitary forces
like Assam rifles I'm talking about the
actual Indian military the same
situation you have with at the border
with Pakistan and China we're going to
have to do the same thing over here
that's going to cause its own set of
problems which I not going okay because
the Armed Forces will also be targeted
the same way they have targeted by the
pakistanis the same thing will
happen so this process of fencing the
border the entire border how long is the
Border let's take a very rough
estimate it's hundreds of kilometers
long it's going to be very difficult to
do it it needs to be done they need to
create border roads all along along the
border it's going to be a long time it
will take minimum 10 to 20 years to do
this and once the border is sealed off
fenced off and no more illegal
infiltrators can cross over then you
need to do a proper survey of all
the illegals who are within Manipur
within mizoram and other parts of India
they need to be identified they need to
be intered and they need to be deported
that is also going to take a long time
it's the long drawn out process that we
have in front of us the first thing that
needs to be done is to seal the
Border that's the first thing that's the
First Step without that nothing will
happen without that nothing will happen
whatsoever and then you cut off the
funding to these us funded organizations
in the Far East of India these are
typically religious organization
organizations whether it's
in Manipur whether it's in nagaland
whether it's in mizoram cut off the
foreign funding to these
organizations needs to be done these
essentially these religious
organizations the church is running the
show over here okay and Mr Neu is the
architect of this Mr Neu ensured that us
missionaries run Riot across the fire
east of India and and and and convert
the locals the indigenous people on an
industrial scale which resulted in a
complete eradication of the beautiful
local culture that's what's happened so
cookie land is already being formed it
is currently under
formation it's a very difficult and
dangerous time for India in the Far East
of India it is a very very tough time
for the indigenous people of
Manipur and it's going to be a long
journey ahead minimum 20 years but India
needs to start acting right now start
fencing off the Border it's going to
take time but start now that's what
India needs to
do okay Sun Moon 00 Sun Moon 0877 and
herel Agarwal 922
say what's the reason for
muu Mr Pazuzu Mr
uh the leader of the Maldives who went
from saying India out to India in and
did the Maldives give India 28 Islands
or is it fake news if it's true then
what made them gift Islands just like
our magnificent Shri Pandit G Shu G so
uh first of all uh uh what happened is
that our foreign minister Dr J Shankar
was in the Maldives about a week or so
ago okay on on on an official visit to
the males and India and the maldiv
signed a whole bunch of agreements and a
lot of projects of various kinds are
going to be undertaken by India so for
example there's going to be India is
going to be
undertaking the project of constructing
sewerage system sewage systems on 28
islands in the Maldives so the Maldives
is not handing over 28 Islands to India
it has uh signed projects with India
India so it's handed projects to India
for various uh sewage system
Construction
on 28 Islands so that's fake news that
they have given 28 Islands to India they
have we will be doing projects on these
28 Islands that's number one okay so
that's that takes care of that second
question the one by hsel um now the
question is what happened what on Earth
is going on in the Maldives what on
Earth is happening in the Maldives Mr
muu was rabidly anti- India wasn't he he
has been running this anti what India
out campaign for
years and the moment he comes to power
he says the Indian uh military personnel
who have there a handful of Indian
military personnel who were there they
had to leave the country and so on so
forth so what happened suddenly why this
sudden U-turn they asked India to leave
to to leave and and you know not
continue any of the projects India was
doing there and suddenly they're signing
agreements with India for many more
projects and whatnot what is happening
is the question what is happening so
once again let's go to the map to
understand where the Maldives is it is
an extension of the lakad
archipelago and this is the males very
pretty set of
islands uh the people obviously are of
Indian origin and so on uh so understand
this my friends the Maldives are whether
you like it or not the fact is that the
Maldives are to
today a Chinese proxy so India is
surrounded by Foreign proxies okay
Pakistan is a US proxy Afghanistan is a
US proxy uh Burma is under Civil War it
will soon be a us proxy kiland
Bangladesh is a US proxy Sri Lanka you
can say is kind of a US proxy Nepal
unfortunately is a Chinese proxy and so
on everybody around India is a proxy
India is the only Sovereign Nation left
so males is today Chinese proxy okay the
pro India government lost the the
election and Mr muu came to power and he
is very strongly pro-china his first
foreign visit was to China he he met
with Mr Shu Jinping and so on so then
now the question is now it becomes even
stranger why is a strongly pro-china
government signing all these deals with
India agreements with India and handing
over so many projects to India what on
Earth happened why this incredible
U-turn that is the question now the
answer to that question could perhaps
lie in a tweet that I put out a few days
ago here's the tweet I put this tweet
out on the 13th of August today is what
18th of August 5 days ago I said the
Americans are going to achieve the
unthinkable they are going to drive
India and China into the same
camp that's what I said a few days ago
and you're kind of beginning to see that
you're kind of beginning to see that so
of very strongly pro-china government in
Maldives is
now making amends with India making
friends with
India okay there are no coincidences in
in
geopolitics nothing happens without a
reason uh if
you if you uh see the Chinese embassy's
Twitter account uh of late they have
been
extremely generous in their tweets about
India extremely positive tweets about
India if you see the global times which
used to be I have covered that in the
past the global times and the tweets it
puts out and the stories and the um and
the analysis it puts out it's a Chinese
propaganda Outlet the global global
times so if you look at the global times
uh articles about India in the past few
weeks they are all
positive something is changing in the
world
and ually the Americans may be taking it
too far and they may end up actually
achieving the unthinkable they may
actually push India and China into the
same cap it doesn't mean that India and
China is are going to be friends okay it
doesn't mean that you still got to be
very careful about the
Chinese but out of necessity it looks
like India and China may have to make
up and
well let's see how that goes but you are
seeing signs of that very strong
pro-china government in the Maldives is
now making friendly overtures to India
very very drastic shift from its policy
just a few months ago so we are seeing
that we are seeing a significant
shift in the
region in the India China relationship
very rapid geopolitical change this year
and this decade like I've said
before okay Ma chacher says uh
Pakistan's former isi Chief F Hamid
lieutenant general f Hamid was recently
arrested on corruption charges what do
you believe are the real reasons behind
his arrest do you think this development
will will impact the military as an
institution and potentially create
divisions within it yeah interesting
news lieutenant general fiz f
amid I hope I'm getting the rank right U
he has been
arrested um and he was was a very
powerful man until recently I remember
when when Kabul fell to the Taliban he
was in a hotel in Kabul sipping chai and
making all kinds of grandio statements
and the people at the time were
interpreting this as a victory for the
isi for for for Pakistan that is has won
Pakistan has won and they will now take
over Afghanistan turns out it wasn't the
case but so that's the guy lieutenant
general f Hamid he has now been arrested
on corruption charges and I haven't gone
into the details of what charges are
there against him the question like
Mazer asks is what are the real reasons
behind this so generally you will find
that the Army always takes care in
Pakistan the Pakistani army the
Pakistani military always takes care of
its
men okay they never go against their own
people so what happened here why have
they arrested this guy that's a question
now to understand that go back a couple
of
years uh until 2022 first quarter of the
Year Mr Imran Khan was
the Prime Minister of Pakistan wasn't he
and then it was depos
n and Mr Imran Khan was deposed in a
coup because he was very strongly
pro-china and the Americans intervened
and they got him out and now there is a
very strongly Pro US government in power
in Pakistan the prime Minister obviously
is is just a puppet the real power is in
the hands of the military and the
military is now very strongly Pro us and
they pay homage to the US they they
visit Washington DC Langley Etc and they
meet with the US defense establishment
and so on they top brass Etc so it's
known to happen yeah so the so the
Pakistani military is now firmly in the
lap of the US of the superpower no
longer with China and that was signaled
by the housting of Mr Imran Khan now
it who was Mr Imran Khan's right-hand
man in the Pakistani military well there
you have it Mr not Mr lieutenant general
f amid he was Imran Khan's Confidant so
to say he was Imran Khan's best friend
so to say and he was his well main man
in the Pakistani military so now that
things are being put in place in the
Indian subcontinent Bangladesh has been
taken care of by the Americans so they
also want to consolidate their hold on
Pakistan and one of the ways of doing it
is to weed out or Purge like the Chinese
say all potentially anti- us
elements so Mr F lieutenant general f z
may not have been anti us but he was pro
pro China wasn't he well he and Mr Imran
Khan were Pro China so he is being taken
out and I'm sure there's going to be a
deeper Purge within not just
P zamid but many other people will be
targeted in this this is called a purge
a purge in the Communist Lang
lingo communist terminology for this
sort of event is a purge there's a purge
that's ongoing in the Pakistani military
establishment and I'm I can assure I can
I can't assure you but I'm pretty
certain it's it's being done at the
behest of the US clean up your ranks get
rid of anybody who could potentially be
anti- us or who has anti- us track
record or or pro-china track record so
there's a lot more beyond what I'm
saying in this I'm sure there's a very
complicated web tangled web of things
but uh overall he was Mr Iman Khan's
right-hand man he was his Confidant best
friend whatever you want to call it and
he was Pro China and because of his
association with Imran Khan who has been
purged he's also being purged so that's
probably what is happening in Pakistan
okay another question by maer chater I
recently watched a video on YouTube
where a Vic astrologer predicted that
Pakistan May might no longer exist in
its current form by the years 2027 28
given the current political instability
economic crisis and internal divisions
within the military in Pakistan how do
you view this prediction as a
geopolitical analyst do you believe
Pakistan is heading in that
direction okay uh so I I know nothing
about astrology Vic astrology so I can't
comment I can't possibly comment about
that
now what's the
possibility what's the likelihood what's
the probability that Pakistan will break
up by the year
2728 given that that's about three or
four years from now we are in the year
2024 well see Pakistan I I will tell you
will exist as long as the US needs it to
exist okay map where's the map here's
the map so Pakistan
is a very important client State puppet
state of the US and Bangladesh or east
Pakistan is a newly minted client State
puppet state vasal state wasal of the US
so the US has two wasal on India's
eastern and for Western borders Pakistan
and East Pakistan or Bangladesh now
these nations from the US perspective
are very important they're vital for
keeping India under check keeping India
counterbalanced off balance
so Pakistan is very important and as
long as the Americans need Pakistan to
exist it will keep on existing because
they will keep on supporting it and
they're really good at this they're
really good at propping up client states
puppet dictatorships vasal they really
good at that so Pakistan will exist as
long as the Americans need it to exist
and so I don't see it breaking up
anytime soon okay but you never know
something may happen something complet
completely unforeseen may happen and it
and things will move in a certain
direction but overall it looks like the
Americans are going to be targeting
India uh with the objective of of of uh
arresting India's growth or or delaying
India's growth as long as possible next
10 20 years so maybe the need Pakistan
to exist for at least 10 20 years in
that case so yeah it's it's very hard to
make any predictions uh
so I want Venture and make a prediction
but I think it is less likely that
Pakistan will break up uh or no longer
exist in its current form by the year
2728 Pakistan most likely may continue
to exist in this current form
Beyond 2728 that's what I think maybe
I'm wrong but who
knows okay Sun Moon 0877 says when will
the US big dad Empire fall if the US
Empire Falls will Russia be the next
superpower where do you see bat's
position 100 years from now look there's
a lot of talk about us
Decline and so on I disagree the US may
be declining as a society its values and
morals and ethics may be declining the
equality of its people may be declining
okay its education system will be
declining it's uh economy
or the domestic economy inflation Etc
may be may be in bad shape okay uh there
may be all kinds of Divisions within the
country lack of trust it's now a low
trust Society there is more homelessness
more crime all kinds of problems so
internally the US Society is in Decline
sure I agree but as an Empire what are
the characteristics of an Empire it's
hard power it's military strength it's
economic strength its power projection
capabilities I promise you I assure you
the US has been has never been more
powerful than it is today I think the US
is is at the peak of its hard
power it has military power projection
capabilities globally it can intervene
militarily at 30 minutes notice anywhere
on the
planet it can annihilate and flatten Any
Nation it wants I promise you that it
can do that momentarily if it
wants so from that perspective the US is
very far away from falling or declining
its hard power is actually
Rising okay uh yeah economically there
there could be some concerns about the
about the long-term viability of the US
dollar Etc but I'm sure they can handle
that as well I'm sure they have a plan
for that as
well and so so I don't see this Empire
falling anytime soon unless it it it
falls from within so if you look at the
history of great
Empires whether it's the Roman Empire
whether it's the morian Empire whether
it is the
Persian Empire whichever Empire you want
to talk about
okay these Empires they always fall
because of internal problems problems
within that weaken that Empire from
inside inside out
and that typically manifests itself
in in a variety of ways in the nation's
society and and and the the the quality
of its military architecture of its
decision-making process of the of the
government bureaucracy and Machinery Etc
so that's where the decline becomes
apparent right now the decline is
apparent in the US Society only not
overall in their military machine of
course there are certain ideologies that
are creeping into the US military which
may precipitate a decline in
standards uh if that happens it could
fall
unexpectedly but I don't see it falling
anytime soon I think the US Primacy
supremacy of the world hemony of the
world
will last for the foreseeable future
maybe at least until
2050 I think it's too early to start
talking about a you the fall of the US
Empire uh and with the Advent of
Technologies like AI Etc Quantum
Computing and so on they could end up
ruling for another 200 years who knows
who knows you never know so I think it's
too early to start speculating about
when the US Empire will fall I think
it's extraordinarily powerful it's the
most powerful Empire that has ever
existed in the history of humankind and
it's right now at the peak of its hard
power strength okay so yeah that's where
they are now if the US Empire does fall
for whatever reason who's going to be
the next superpower probably it'll be
Russia or maybe
China uh the Russians have an
unmatchable nuclear Arsenal the Chinese
can't catch up with that but the Chinese
have probably the world's largest Navy
in terms of numbers numerically largest
dvy and they have probably better
technology and all so then if the US
Empire Falls for whatever reason it's
going to be a
fight between China and Russia and
that's when these two Nations will
become hostile towards each other so
I've always said this that China and
Russia are long-term adversaries not
partners and in the Advent of in the in
the in the event of something like the
US Empires un likely Fall these the
hostility between the two Nations China
and Russia will come out in the open
almost
instantly where do I see bat's position
100 years from now I think by 2100 if we
really play our cards right we could be
the world's largest
economy okay if we don't get caught up
in bad luck and if everything works out
fine if we don't get embroiled in any
major military conflict and we are able
to withstand the US pressure on us and
other pressures on us so in the best
case scenario we are the world's largest
economy by
2100 uh so that I'm an optimistic person
and that's where I see it going and if
we are the world's largest economy by 21
100 we will also be the largest military
so yeah and hopefully we will have by
that time learned the lessons of the
past 1,000 years so we're going to be a
whole different Beast if that happens if
we do end up becoming the world's
largest economy that's a long time away
from now so you don't
know okay two questions about
kskk geopolitical Dub and Muhammad
ismile is it true that Ukraine captured
some Russian controlled territory what's
the current situation in the Ukraine and
what developments are occurring in
Russia's Kursk Kursk region and for what
factors have led to the vulner
vulnerability of Russia's border with
Ukraine could this be attributed to
shortcomings within the Russian military
or possibly to corruption okay let's
take a look at the map what's going
on so here we are in
Ukraine and east of Ukraine you have in
the northeast of Ukraine to the of the
Northeast east border of Ukraine you
have Kursk oblast Kursk region let's say
Kur District or whatever you want to
call it this is where the Ukrainian
military has made an incursion it's not
an invasion it's an incursion it's like
a limited uh uh entry into Russian
territory so they made good progress and
they captured a sizable amount of
territory and now they are being pounded
and driven back so what does this mean
does could this be attributed to Short
comings in the Russian military or
corruption I don't know about corruption
but definitely it looks like the
Russians were kind of caught off guard
they probably did not expect this to
happen maybe the Americans or NATO
supplied Ukraine with whatever Weaponry
they needed and all that and they were
able to make a brief incursion into the
region but now they are being driven
back and uh the Russians will prevail
the Russians have a much more capable
military they have
essentially
extremely uh deep stocks of arms and
ammunition the ukrainians don't have
that and the Russians have much more
manpower so the Russians are going to
eventually Prevail in this matter and
things will go back on track the way
they were so that's the current
situation in
Ukraine uh overall it's been a very slow
very long War kind of scenario Frozen
conflict kind of scenario the Russians
are willing to wait as long as they need
they are in no hurry but their eventual
long-term objective is the
denazification of Ukraine regime change
in Kiev a pro Russia regime in Kev and
the permanent neutralization of Ukraine
in in the sense that Ukraine becomes
permanently neutral neither Pro West nor
Pro Russia just neutral so that's what
the Russians want and that's what they
will achieve unless NATO can spring a
genuine
surprise so look the Russian border with
Ukraine is extremely large and it's very
it's not fenced off it's not de I mean
it is demarcated but it is not fenced
off so it is
possible uh for sufficiently well-armed
Force to make a surprise attack and make
an incursion obviously there's going to
be an investigation in Russia as to how
this was allowed to happen blah blah
blah and so on but overall Russia is
kind of doing fine that's what I can say
I can't possibly comment about any
possible corruption Etc in the Russian
military I have no information about
that shortcomings certainly there could
be some shortcomings which the Russians
would want to address I suppose
yep okay Malik said says would we see a
monotheism versus polytheism conflict
soon in geopolitics because one would
observe patterns realigning in that way
in the world order basically abrahamic
religions versus dhic religions or
Eastern religions well the past 1500 or
so years it's been that sort of thing
it's been a monotheistic religion versus
polytheistic religions abrahamic
religions versus Eastern religions so to
say or or or old religions so for
example uh if you go to the map of
Europe uh you
had you know U so when it comes to the
Eastern Roman Empire the Byzantine
Empire which was based out of
Constantinople which is currently
Istanbul uh this Empire became
officially Christian sometime in the
fourth or so Century ad you can look up
the exact date when it was Emperor
Constantine made Christianity the
official religion and then there was
large scale persecution of
non-christians people who believed in
the old gods the old religion uh in the
region all the way up to Egypt
Alexandria Etc because all all of that
was part of the extended Empire at
various points in time and then
Christianity became the
official religion of the Roman Eastern
Roman EMP the Vatican and so on and then
there was a Christian conquest of Europe
and that was pretty brutal that was
pretty brutal and the where's the book I
don't I don't know where it is but I
have this book by Katherine Nixie
Katherine Nixie called the darkening age
in which she speaks about the Christian
destruction of the old religion and old
way of life so if you go to Greece today
you will see all these old monuments old
statues and you will see that every
single one of these statues the old
statues of the old Greek gods each one
of these statues is defaced broken faces
broken arms broken legs broken breasts
whatever right so there was this
systematic destruction of the old
polytheistic religion and the culture uh
and most wars in those days of Conquest
were obviously fought for plunder and uh
and territory and all that but they were
fought in the name of
religion so these were Wars for
Christianity Wars for Conquest for
Christianity for the glory of Christ and
with the Advent of Islam the similar
thing happened most of these wars were
jihads they were there's no controversy
about that and they were for fought in
the name of of of Islam right so it for
the past 1500 plus years it's been that
way monotheism versus polytheism and
monotheism has been the dominant force
in the world because of its uniquely
milit militaristic structure the command
and control structure that monotheistic
religions and societies
have uh so that's been that way but now
of late the West has been espousing
democracy and all that in
secularism uh so they cannot they cannot
uh portray their conquests today as
conquests of religion but there is no
secret about the fact that they
prefer uh monotheism and they don't
understand polytheism and polytheism is
problematic because it is hard to
control and hard hard to control such
such a society hard to unify such such a
society monotheistic societies are very
very easy to control
so overall it's going to be like that
it's been like that the past 1500 plus
years the 1,000 years in the past
Millennium during which India was
occupied first by the Turks and then by
the Europeans mainly that was occupation
in the name of religion of course they
the the the Europeans they came to trade
but then they found that India was weak
at the time so they took over but there
was a religious angle to that as well
when it comes to the turky occupation of
India it was pretty much straightfor
religious War you know uh so yeah that's
what you have and
uh so geopolitics has multiple levels
you you have what's visible and then
there are these
implied
subur in what happens and there is
obviously a religious angle as well so
the Americans they use whatever means
they have at their disposal when it
comes to India's Far East Northeast
they've been using religion very
successfully Baptist missionaries
running Riot across the Far East of
India converting people on an industrial
scale and compromising the the security
safety Etc Integrity of India that's
been happening for a long time so
religion is very much a factor in
essentially everything look at what's
happened the past five six seven decades
in South Korea for example okay South
Korea most people today identify either
as atheists or Christians the Buddhists
have become a minority in South Korea
and the similar thing could be happening
in Japan most people identify as atheist
now so wherever the Americans have a
footprint look at what happened in the
Philippines okay the Americans aren't
responsible for the christianization of
the Philippines it's the Spanish who did
that but you see that everywhere so yeah
and religion is used as a means of
controlling foreign countries so it's
going to be that way
yes r sarar always asks great questions
so uh recently I was searching on the
internet for some major events in the
Cold War era there were mentions of the
Berlin airlift the Yum kipur War um
Prague the Prague spring the Su crisis
the Bay of Pigs invasion CU Cuban
Missile Crisis Korean War Vietnam War
Etc in all these sites websites but
there were very few mentions very less
mentions of the Sino Indian war or the
Indo Pakistan wars of 71 or or the 1971
Bangladesh Liberation War why is that
well I think it's a good wakeup call for
Indians it tells you that India is not
was not important in the 20th century
during the Cold War era India did not
matter India was an
insignificant Nation if India went to
war with China it was a small local
Regional war no one cared it was a big
event for India but the rest of the
world didn't care it did not matter it
did not affect the rest of the world if
India and Pakistan fought
65 uh what 48 65 71 97 98 whichever year
it was didn't matter the rest of the
world didn't care it did not affect or
impact the rest of the
world nice nice effect
so so yeah that's why you
see India was not that important at the
time India is somewhat more important
today but at the time no one cared so if
India went to war with Pakistan or China
or whatever it did not make much of a
difference to the rest of the world and
that's why these are those are not the
big events of the Cold War era the Bay
of Pigs invasion was kind of turning
point in the Cold War it failed because
John F Kennedy refused to provide air
support or whatever to the invasive
invading forces and that is allegedly
what led to his what happened in
1963 J assassination okay apparently a
lone Gun Man from the back what absolute
nonsense Warren Commission report or
whatever it was uh okay I I digress so
India wasn't that important that's why
no one speaks about it
right rodra sarar again says can you
tell us something about sh the G the
great French leader of the 20th century
who is this guy T the ghou so he is one
of the Colossal figures the Colossal
figure of 20th Century France
essentially so who was this guy and why
is he so important so Char the gold was
born in the late 19th century in France
and he came from a religious Catholic
Family patriotic family he attended a
religious school apparently Jesuit
school or something and he joined the
military and he fought in the in the
first world war the first World War was
between 1914 and 19 1918 1919 whichever
year it was so sh the was a junior
military officer in the in the first
world war he was captured in the Battle
of vda I
believe captured by the Germans and he
spent the rest of the war the remainder
of the war as a prisoner of war in
Germany so he he was in captivity in
Germany after 1916 until the end of the
war of the first world war so then the
first world war ends and Germany is
humiliated horribly and obviously sha
the go is released and he continues his
military career he was a teacher a
professor at theol milit the military
school in in France he wrote several
books military strategy Etc during this
time period and then you have the second
world war second world war starts in
what
1939 somewhere of that so around that
time he gets a promotion he's promoted
to what general Brigadier something like
that and uh he sees a lot of action in
the second world war Germany invades
France obviously Germany occupies France
so France is defeated and Germany
occupies France and shall the goal he
fled to London he crossed the English
Channel fled to London and from there he
organized the French Resistance against
Nazi Germany and once the French once
once France was uh liberated from
Germany he came back to France and he
headed the French government the French
provisional government uh after 1944 I
think and then there were problems and
disagreements political disagreements so
he resigned couple of years after that
and then eventually he returned to power
during the Algerian War there was this
Algerian war war between France and
Algeria it was the war of Algerian
Independence 1950s
1960s it it it ended sometime in the
early 60s
6162 it started sometime in the 1950s I
don't know which year 55 54 look it up
look it up okay I don't remember all the
exact dates so Char the gold came back
to Power he returned to politics during
this war the Algerian Independence War
he became the Prime Minister he created
the fifth Republic he uh it came with a
new Constitution and so on he becomes
the first president and he served as
president for a decade he oversaw the
the uh independence of
Algeria and he was a proponent of a very
strong foreign policy he chaed at France
being under the boots of
NATO France was a part of NATO and NATO
what was NATO NATO was the US occupation
of Western Europe so after the second
world war the US decided that the best
course of action for was for America to
stay in Europe not leave
Europe okay and they form NATO and
France becomes a part of NATO and that
was that that you have to give up give
up some of your sovereignty to Nato so
Char the go he he was a strong advocate
for a strong and independent France and
he withdrew France from NATO's military
command in the 60s
1960s and he actually wanted good
relations with the Soviet
Union and he also opposed uh American
dominance in the world so that's how it
happened and eventually he
resigned as president in the late
60s and a year or so later he died so he
is remembered as this great French
leader Statesman a towering figure in
French history he was a great Soldier he
fought in two world wars and he is kind
of one of the architects who shaped the
modern day France so that is Char the G
Gul means the pre-christian France it
was called gold it was the Celtic France
so sh the go means sh of
go and go is like I said the ancient
name of France and his political ideas
policies ideology is called
gism okay so that is in brief about Miss
sh the g a great man of
France so it's good to get a few
questions that I haven't answered before
I don't think I've spoken about Char the
go before so there you have it let's
take another question that I probably
may not have answered before Again by r
sarar can you tell us something about
the sa Revolution why did it happen and
how did India and Pakistan react to this
development so the S Revolution was a
revolution that happened in
Afghanistan in gandhar it happened I
believe in
1978 right uh April 1978 and that month
is called saus sa aw or sa in the the in
in Afghanistan okay so this was the sa
Revolution was essentially a Communist
Revolution it was a Keta that happened
in April
1978 excuse me and uh it led to the
overthrow of the government of the then
president Muhammad daud Khan in
Afghanistan and this Kuda brought to
power a Marxist Communist party in
Afghanistan the people's Democratic
party of Afghanistan PD DPA
yes that was a s Revolution so why did
this happen why did the S Revolution
happen it happened because of because
this guy daud Khan had very strong had a
very apparently authoritarian regime and
there were economic problems and social
inequalities and there was strong
influence of communist ideology
apparently in the military and this
party and there were political tensions
between daud Khan and this political
party the pdpa and dud Khan arrested
several important or key pdpa leaders
and this is what triggered the coup okay
that's what happened so daud Khan was
overthrown the pdpa comes to power and
uh some leader I forget the name okay he
becomes the president after the
Revolution and there's there there there
are a couple of guys whose names I
cannot remember right now who become
president one after the other so the
objective
the objective of this party was to
establish a Marxist communist government
in Afghanistan and to implement
socialist reforms land redistribution
educational St stages changes
modernization of Afghanistan reduce the
influence of tribal leaders religious
leaders and on and so on so forth so
what this did okay is that a communist
government came to power they initiated
very strong radical reforms
in Afghanistan impose those those
reforms on the Afghanistan people
population with and the Afghan Society
at the time was very conservative very
traditional so these reforms were highly
unpopular and because of that there was
a lot of resistance there was a lot of
unrest especially among the Islamic
fundamentalist groups in Afghanistan and
that led to the kind to a kind of Civil
War kind of situation and the pdpa
government came under a lot of pressure
and
stress and the USSR became
concerned let's go to the map why
haven't I shown the map so north of
Afghanistan you have Turkmenistan
usbekistan Tajikistan all that which was
then part of the USSR so because the
government PDP a government came under
stress the USSR became concern and
that's why the USSR launched an invasion
of Afghanistan and that led to the
Afghan Civil War the Americans got
involved because they did not want the
USSR to
have a new stronghold in the region and
that went on for years and years until
the late 1980s eventually the pdpa
government was overthrown Muhammad najah
had to go and take refuge in the
Consulate in the Vatican consulate I
believe in in in was it
Kandahar and eventually the northern uh
the the mujahedin
captured him
and did what they did to him long story
short so that was a s Revolution that is
what triggered the Soviet invasion
eventually of
Afghanistan animish
6245 says what makes uh the
Jews so firm and aggressive while us
Hindus are so docile and forgiving both
of the communities experien the same
atrocities and ethnic cleansing for
centuries what makes one different from
the other well the first difference is
is the difference between monotheism and
polytheism Jews Jewish people are a
monotheistic culture monotheistic people
Hinduism is a wildly polytheistic
culture very different extremely
different like they say difference
between Heaven and
Earth incredible difference so
fundamentally different societies first
of all okay there is that uh then I
think the Jews have been much smarter
than the Hindus and
understand the the the benefit of
sticking together as a as a culture as a
people
um and uh yeah I think these are the two
fundamental differences they have been
much smarter than than Hindus they have
stuck together they have always been
United um Hindus are never United
despite having a nation it's not a Hindu
Nation uh the Jewish people have a
Jewish nation and they have interests
all across the world and because of
their strong political Unity Etc they
can get things done in other countries
as well so it is something that is very
admirable I would say what the Jewish
people have achieved despite facing so
many struggles obstacles challenges all
kinds of atrocities for 2,000 plus years
but they have survived and endured and
that's something I suppose Hindus can
learn from the Jewish people
right dunger sing Johan says what what
are your thoughts about the recent
outbreak of monkey box and why is Africa
so regular in gifting these deadly
viruses to the world um okay first of
all let's talk about Africa and viruses
you know there's a lot of viruses that
have actually truthfully you're right
lots of let's I would not say
interesting viruses from a scientific
perspective it's interesting but yeah
lots of deadly viruses have emerged out
of various parts of Africa Congo what's
that cave called I forget the cave I've
read the book about that you know
there's the marberg virus there is the
Ebola virus there are various other
viruses West Nile Virus Ebola is
frightening very high mortality rate and
so on lots of weird and extremely deadly
virulent viruses emerge Out of Africa
also China let's not forget China the
recent events were all China aren't
there bhan um and now there is the the
the wh is talking about this new
outbreak and they are classifying it as
something of extreme concern I believe
monkey pox
monkey box is a it's a viral thing I
think and uh it it uh it's it it has
symptoms similar to measles or chicken
pox or something but I'm not sure I've
not read it up actually so I would not
don't take this as medical advice at all
okay so what are my thoughts I think
it's concerning I hope it doesn't become
a new pandemic that's the last thing we
need in the
world I think those two or three lost
years were enough we never want to see
that again I'm obviously talking about
the Corona virus pandemic the Wuhan
virus pandemic so we never want to see
that sort of thing again I hope that uh
if they if it is genuinely U an outbreak
of concern it is addressed very very
strongly and robustly and stemmed out
before it can uh propagate anywhere so I
think it's something we need to keep a
very close watch
on and hopefully it's not another
exercise
in in uh
filling the coffers of vaccine companies
I hope it's not that again that's all I
will say about
that okay Lisa Rose says why were the
British so successful in colonization
it's not like everyone in the world is
weak dumb or easy to influence and plus
why do Indians always get easily
influenced when we are also some of the
most hardworking and smartest people on
Earth okay the question is why were the
British so successful in colonization
the British were so successful for in
colonization for for a number of reasons
first of all they
perfected the
organized uh
application of violence they perfected
it the systematic and organized
application of violence
replicable repeatable processes and and
procedures and
systems so first of all perfected the
systematic and organized application of
violence they developed systems of
violence very good
weapons uh
they they deconstructed societies and
identified their weak points in possible
areas that could be exploited to divide
societies and by that they perfected the
the the the the strategy of divide and
Rule divide and conquer divide and
conquer divide and Rule
and of course they perfected the
creation of Supply chains Etc which
essentially is what underpins the
current uh us hegemony of the
world the US have Supply chains all
across the world every kind of supply
chain you can imagine the Americans have
that and they safeguard that with their
military bases across the world the
British started that so that's why the
British were successful in colonization
it's not about how strong how powerful
How brave you are it's all about systems
and processes that's what leads to
success and the British perfected this
the British like they themselves like to
say are a nation of House of of
bookkeepers merchants but Merchants who
who perfected these things the
systematic application of violence and
Supply chains and that's why they were
so successful in in
colonization so the rest of the world I
think was less smart than the British
when you to give it to them uh and
probably less evil maybe yeah and uh
Indians why do they get so easily
influenced Etc because Indians have an
inferiority complex that's been
ingrained Among Us for the best part
of a century and a half maybe two
centuries maybe more the Millennium of
humiliation so Indians the past thousand
years or so slowly started seeing
themselves as not very powerful not
strong destined to lose destined to have
bad luck so so forth and these days is
there is this mental colonization
because of the English language the
education system and so on so Indians
have this inferiority complex that
foreigners are better white white-
skinned people are better than brown
skinned people and all that that's
something I have never suffered from but
Indians unfortunately do and that is
what's something that infuriates me no
end but that's where we are today it's
because of this
mental uh brainwashing colonization
mental colonization mental conditioning
whatever you want to call call it that's
why they have this Indians are like this
that's why the Indians are like
this okay Priyanka tan says in today's
day and age how does one determine if a
particular news Outlet is reporting the
truth or not I have been following
example a for almost a year now to get
my daily D daily dose of news but of
late I've been observing that the anchor
has been
quoting certain very controversial news
outlets like the print I'll say Okay
example b c d Etc and that's really
making me question the Integrity of this
particular channel can we not trust any
news channel or journalist in today's
times are they all sold out to their
anti-india
masters okay what's the deal look media
is an industry it's a business they have
to make
money they are not in this business for
the purpose of spreading
truths they in the this business to make
for the purpose of making money and to
make money you need people to give you
money so you can either have a business
model in which you have advertisements
and the advertisers pay you money or you
can have people who sponsor your news
and they pay you money but then you have
to dance according to the
tunes okay so in today's day and age you
cannot genuinely rely on any single news
Outlet you simply can't today you only
have narratives you don't really have
the truth truly understand what's really
happening you need to have a very strong
grasp of world history of the cause
causality change cause and effect chain
and you need to still be able to take a
360 degree view at what everybody is
saying and then use your best judgment
to understand what's truly happening
it's it's not easy yeah so how do you
know
whether a certain news Outlet is
reporting truthfully or not so first of
all nobody's going to report truthfully
there's going to always going to be some
bias but let's say you
have 10 let's say French news outlets
okay 10 news outlets in in France now if
you are French I would say you have some
kind of you need to have some kind of
loyalty to your country and you should
have some kind of loyalty to the to your
nation's interest so the first red flag
to look out for is when a media Outlet
is reporting an is is is spreading a
narrative that goes counter to their own
nation's interest that is the first red
flag you have to look out for but for
that you have to understand what is that
nation's interest so forget about France
look at India hopefully we have a
reasonably good understanding of what
constitutes the Indian national interest
right hopefully most of us have some
idea of what our national interest is
now look at all the media Outlets there
are so many right and ask yourself
which of these Outlets not one but
multiple I'm sure I'm sure which of
these Outlets consistently reports many
stories that create a narrative that is
counter to India's national interest let
ask us of that that
question that that should give you a
reasonably good
answer so that's how it goes there is no
truth anymore today it's all narratives
you either have a pro- nation narrative
or an anti- nation narrative and the
truth sometimes is somewhere in between
okay
but you got to be loyal to your nation
to your people to your nation's interest
and many of these media Outlets
are spreading narratives that go counter
to the nation's interest in that case
what you can do is you can dig a little
deeper and see who's funding them and
then who is funding those funders and
who's controlling the funders and then
very interesting stories come out it's
not hard to hard to to
to to discover not very hard to discover
and then it becomes very clear who is
actually out there to to harm India
which nations are out there to harm
India it's generally one or two Nations
The Usual Suspects but it takes time to
do this it takes hard work to do this
you got to do a lot of
digging you need to know how to dig how
to look where to look for all and all
that but if you do it you will discover
the truth it's not that hard to discover
okay K list says
fungi that can absorb radiation have
been growing all over the Chernobyl
nuclear power plant the ruined Chernobyl
nuclear power plant could you explain
how this process
occurs okay interesting yes so there
have been news reports of a certain
species or a certain set of species of
fungi
fungus and that's been growing all over
the walls of this Chernobyl power plant
which is very dangerous power plant
because it's we know what happened in
1986 it essentially exploded and it
spewed nuclear material all over the
place radioactive material all over the
place and it is still a major nuclear
Hazard a tremendous amount of radiation
is still coming out of the place it's
going to continue for probably thousands
of years okay so and yet over there on
the walls of the building and the
control panels and all that there's this
fungus that's spreading all all over the
place a very dark
fungus and uh it's been discovered that
this fungus
actually absorbs the radiation and uses
that as as as as fuel for growing so I
think it's
called radiosynthetic fungus or
something so when you have plant you
know PL plants with green leaves they
absorb
sunlight and that is a process called
photosynthesis and you have molecules
like ATP Etc and there's a whole bi
biochemical process that happens and
that's how plants uh absorb energy from
sunlight and turn that into fuel for
growth and so on so forth so these fungi
are doing the same thing but not with
sunlight they're doing it with radiation
gamma and Alpha Beta gamma whatever
probably gamma radiation
gamma radiation is photons but extremely
high energy photons sunlight is like
regular energy that we are used to it
isn't really harmas but gamma ray
photons are extraordinarily more
energetic than sunlight photons so
that's what these fungi are absorbing
and they are somehow converting that the
energy of those photons into into into
energy that they can use so these fungi
they they have a pigment called melanin
so melanin is something all humans have
okay to whatever extent the more melanin
you have in your skin the darker skin
you have and the less melanin you have
the lighter skin you are that's how it
is so everybody has some melanin In
Their Skin these fungi have me melanin
and the the photons the gamma ray
photons or whatever maybe it's electrons
beta Rays or whatever it is or Alpha
Rays helium nuclei whatever radiation it
is is hitting this these melanin
molecules and somehow it's exciting
electrons and somehow for by some
process it is U allowing these fungi to
use that as energy and probably convert
that into something that is usable in
some form so I'm not sure if this the
the biologist scientists Etc have
exactly determined how it's happening
but that's kind of how it is happening
these are fungi very unusual fungi fungi
that have melanin and they are using
radiosynthesis to to grow and to thrive
that's what's happening in
brief JM says as an older generation
person what's your opinion on the growth
of the country how much has India or
Barat changed since your childhood and
youth in terms of show social economic
and environmental conditions for better
or
worse right so when I was a little kid
look I was born in 1976 okay in the
winter in the Autumn of
76 uh that's a long time ago obviously
and I recall when I was a he India was
way less populated than it is today
today India is this bustling place for
full of crowds that time it was not like
that the population was much much lower
than what it is to it was visibly lower
so I think in the 1970s 80s early 80s
India's population must have been around
600 million less than half of what it is
today okay that's how it was that's
number one secondly there was tremendous
poverty compared to what you have today
I recall as a kid it was normal to see
people walking around
barefoot in
cities and the major mode of
transportation for most people was a
bicycle okay that that's the childhood
memories I have and uh in the early
80s most people did not have
televisions okay and people had those
transistor radios and things like that
and then I spent many years abroad out
of the out of the country so when I come
back it's kind of changed but it's still
extremely poor the country and now
everybody has
televisions most people have black and
white
televisions and some people have color
televisions and so on but there is only
one TV channel that across the country
it's called dur dasan and it has a it
has sessions sa sub sa sham sa only a
few hours a day the television channel
is on and it's all typically govern
propaganda an extremely boring
programming and there is no mention of
what's happening outside of India so
India was essentially like North Korea
the the TV news only reported what
ribbon cutting ceremony which minister
attended and what speech which minister
gave that's how it was India was
actually like North Korea extremely
isolated from the rest of the world no
economic growth no prospects the cues
for everything people had to stand in
queue for God knows what items most
people used to used to cook with
kerosene stoves and whatnot everything
was short supply artificial shortages of
everything terrible terrible condition
India was in okay when I was a kid small
kid today's India is is essentially
Heaven compared to what you have today
what you had when I was a little kid
very different India but today's
youngsters won't understand that and
that's the problem we have come a really
long way and uh much of the growth has
happened in more recent times let me
just put it that way so yeah India has
changed tremendously there was no energy
in the country in those days there was
no great sense of Hope in those days
everything progressed the snails snails
pace today people can actually hope
people have big Ambitions today you
didn't have that at the time and there
was no self-confidence among the people
of India at the time today you have it
so India has changed tremendously and it
needs to change even more for the better
so let's all work together to make it
happen Okay Arijit benerji
says I recently got rejected by the girl
of my dreams I'm feeling like a loser
any tips so I can lessen the pain of my
heart oh bro I sorry for what happened
to you sir okay look life is going to be
about a lot of rejection the most
successful people in life are the ones
who have experienced the most
rejection if you are scared of rejection
if one rejection hurts you and it gives
you heart pain or whatever uh you need
to do better than that so firstly I
would say if you have been rejected by
the girl of your dreams don't take it
personally okay don't take it personally
don't take any rejection personally
everybody has certain hopes and
aspirations and some agenda and
maybe it doesn't work with you right
so look if if somebody rejects you it
doesn't mean that it has some it means
you're bad or you you're loser or
something it means that they want that
person wants something else that is
their problem right and it's not like
the girl who rejected you is the only
girl out there there's a million girl
out there girls out there right so the
point
is you've got to learn how to handle
rejection you will not succeed until you
can take rejection in your stride and
not let it affect
you right so that's what I would say so
I would say that if that was the girl of
your dreams then you need to dream
bigger and dream better I'm sure that
the right girl is somewhere out there
waiting for you so there's nothing don't
take it personally mainly if you take it
personally if you take everything that
happens to you personally then you would
always feel like a loser you got to
Simply change your attitude and change
the way you frame
things right so in in in every sphere of
life you're going to have rejection
and the faster you get rejected the
faster you get the data that helps you
understand how to not get rejected and
how to do better so if you want to
succeed in life find ways of getting
rejected more and more often and and
then try to increase your strike rate in
everything in life okay I'm not just
talking about girls okay but overall
that's what I would say so it's no big
deal it's no big deal at all somewhere
out there there's a girl who's the right
girl for you and you will I'm sure
eventually find her so all the best sir
all the best
Arijit okay with that I am done with the
questions for today and I will now take
some questions from the live
chat
so uh go for it ask me questions in the
live chat and we're going to answer as
many of those as we can
yes um
an prakash says top five movies rapid
rated by you look I love movies I've
watched so many movies but one of my
favorite genre is comedy another
favorite genre is science fiction so
what what would I say some random Mars
Attacks uh The Fifth Element the
mask what else would I say the good the
bad the ugly that's Western okay and
maybe uh Interstellar so here we have
five minutes five movies by no means the
top five movies but the first five that
came to my
mind
okay okay let's take some
questions
uh Malik said asks me how many reactions
I got in some things I've got zero
rejections so there you have
it in some things in other things I got
lots of rejections overall you get lots
overall
uh Manish ATI says I was sitting in the
front from first row when I came for a
speaker session at I am Bangalore okay
good good good I must have seen you
there I do have some questions that I
wasn't able to ask you can we connect on
LinkedIn send me an an invite on
LinkedIn and I'll look at do it or you
can ask me questions
here but yeah um nice to have you
here okay now let's take some questions
right
some
um okay what is this soam barab says are
elected representatives needed today the
citizenry can directly Vote or debate on
policy via the web using use blockchain
technology for verification have
appropriate bars for sensitive pivotal
policies Etc
so are elected representatives needed
today um that's a good question the
thing is you can do everything on the
web you can use blockchain etc for
verification but these Technologies are
kind of let's say some of these
Technologies can be compromised the
internet if something is on the internet
if something is Flowing on virtually it
can be intercepted it can be hacked
there is that blockchain
uh what if there is a space weather
event and more than half the computers
in the world get fried you need 51% for
the blockchain to work properly right so
there is that problem also so when you
have such problems you have to fall back
on the old fashioned things of having
actual Representatives but assuming that
the technology is is fail proof and
foolproof maybe you can you can uh you
you
know experiment with a virtual Network
state or something like some
intellectuals like to talk about it's
it's an interesting idea but I would say
one should be careful about trying to
change things that have worked for a
long time of course you need to always
keep progressing and keep improving
things but some things probably are
there for a reason uh so what if you do
a with the entire system of elected
representatives who represent you in
Parliament or whatever and then you put
everything
online and something happens some some
Act of God like they say you know space
weather event um solar storm that that
wipes out your satellites and and Fries
your networks and Fries your computers
systems and all that then what do you do
then you are left with nothing then your
Society can descend into Anarchy and
Chaos so I think considering all these
even though these are remote
possibilities but it's still possible
it's still possible that's why I would
say we should still have elected
representatives uh
yeah Aram says what's the future of
shikina what will be her next
destination I think her destination will
be will be India only what's the future
I think she will stay in India for the
forceable future and it's possible that
the Bangladeshi government the the
puppet government the puppet us us
puppet regime will try to put pressure
on India why why the US to extradite
shik F to Bangladesh for trial or
whatever so and they may perhaps get the
UN involved in that to put additional
pressure on India so India needs to be
prepared for these things but I think
the future is that she's going to stay
in India that's how I see it
going
okay
um mcloven says why are all countries
facing the problem of illegal
immigration from Japan from India to
Japan to Europe this cannot be a
coincidence um when it comes to India we
have had tremendous amount of illegal IM
immigration from Bangladesh and then
ringas have been settled in India by
certain organizations with the
connivance
of what whoever okay so it is estimated
that probably about 100 million
Bangladesh is maybe in India by now it's
possible in 2014 the government was
putting out a figure of 50 million
that's 10 years ago by now it could
possibly be 100 million so that's a
disaster for India actually
foreigners uh leeching away at our
resources and taking getting benefits
that citizens should have so that's bad
so that's the problem that India is
facing Japan is now open to immigration
that's a disaster for Japan I really
really really feel sorry for Japan they
never wanted this but you know they
don't have any control over their
Destiny they are controlled by the US so
now Japan is open for immigration and
the uh what can I say the quality of
immigrants that are coming to Japan
aren't the best isn't the best and then
you have Europe which is being flooded
with immigrants a certain kind of
demographic of immigrants certain age
and ethnic and religious demographic of
of immigrants it's not a coincidence
it's all being done on purpose it is all
being done systematically to essentially
re-engineer the demographics of these
nations on a massive industrial
scale in the case of India it is because
of problems within India
itself we have certain paramilitary
forces that are supposed to safeguard
our borders and it is alleged it has
come out in the media so many times that
they have been essentially in some way
or the other allegedly complicit in
facilitating the the influx of
Bangladesh is into India for a price
allegedly there is that and pol certain
political parties allegedly have been
part of this problem and so on so I
think it was the Central government's
prerogative that even if there is
corruption blah blah blah they should
have ensured that this doesn't happen so
clearly a failure at multiple
levels uh that's what I can see yeah so
there you have there you have
it I'm not taking any P questions today
okay AKA says how can we merge po into
India by being patient so being
patient Pakistan is going to keep on
existing as long as the Americans need
Pakistan to exist that means that India
cannot take po back until for for a
while for a while so my point is India
needs to become so powerful that PO
comes into India automatically without
us trying to take
it that will take time minimum 20 years
of economic growth con consistent
economic growth that's the key to
India's future and in the meanwhile we
should also not neglect other things if
you only focus on the economy and don't
do anything about illegal immigration if
you only focus the on the economy and
don't do anything about education
then you're going to have this big
economy which you're going to hand over
to your enemies so I think the
government needs to wake up from its
Lumber and do something about these
things but overall I think it's a good
government the best we've had for a long
time uh
okay okay Pinky Kumari says I feel
devastated even after being Sikkim state
rank one I couldn't get a medical Ste
seat in my state counseling neat
2023 another day of feeling worse being
a general category student I I I'm so
sorry I it's
terrible uh what can I say about this
being Sikkim state rank one you could
not get a medical
seat that's incredible that tells you
how bad the system is and this is why we
have talented people going out of the
country brain brain drain because the
country doesn't treat them right the
system doesn't treat them right
if you are sikim state rank one and you
can't get a medical
seat it's it's incredible it's it's
shameful that that talented students are
being treated like
this uh so what what I would say is that
look I I know it it hurts I know it
hurts look I've been there okay and uh
the point is you cannot let this
stop
you going forward in your life you tried
something you tried your best I'm sure
you came first in your state and then
you still did not get what you want so
what what can you do now you got to take
a day or two to recover from this and
move on
and try for Plan B in case you have plan
B you clearly are a good student so
you'll do
well so you'll have to find some other
thing and some other thing some other
course of
action and go forward maybe go abroad
you know that's what most talented
students do I don't blame them for that
and I've always said that if you have a
choice between staying in India and
going abroad I would say go abroad try
your luck there do your do your best
gain a lot of experience gain gain a lot
of wealth and then if you feel like it
you come back to India and and help your
country or don't if you don't want
to I I am okay with people even staying
abroad
you know spread Indian genetics and
culture abroad that's fine even that's
fine so pinky I would say I I really
feel sorry for for you and I would say
do not get discouraged do not spend too
much time ping yourself pick yourself up
stand up go back stand up back stand
back on your feet and find the next
thing to do and the point is you clearly
are a very talented person
if you can come first in your state you
clearly are talented so you will do well
the main thing is don't be devastated
don't be dispirited don't give up I'm
sure you're still pretty young right
so you'll do well in life overall but
the main thing is be positive and don't
give up so all the best and thank you
for sharing this it is important to
share these
stories because the country cannot
progress if we keep treating our
talented young citizens and students in
this matter that's terrible but pinky do
not do not give up okay you you will do
well so all the best do
well okay that
that okay let's take some other
questions something
yeah an prakash says any update on the
Israel Palestine conflict the USA seems
to change for
Israel stand seems to CH yeah there's
nothing no big news or no big
development there no big change in that
right now the focus is on the Iran
Israel angle okay the Palestine thing is
already it's going on the Israelis have
pounded Gaza taken out lots of tunnels
taken out lots of terrorists uh
obviously it's caused a lot of
collateral damage civilians Etc and
that's why Israel is under a lot of uh
it's taken a lot of
flak uh from the media but yeah there
there you have it so right now not any
big major
change
uh you you you're very welcome
pinky Aditya Kiker says why are the
white people interested in the cast
system of India is the cast system is
probably present in every culture yeah
every culture has what you could call a
cast system and the Japanese they have
the
burakumin the French have the
kago and there's much more there's much
more every country has its own cast
system and that is essentially the
system of division of labor you need
division of labor right for any
functioning Society but India has to be
singled out Hindus have to be singled
out the white people the westerners are
interested in the C system of India
because they want to use it to portray
India as a very evil backward Society
that's what it is okay to perpet to to
to to perpetuate the atrocity narrative
that the that the missionaries created
in the 18th and 19th centuries so that
that's what it is okay that's why they
are interested in
this uh
geopolitical dub says I want purchase an
affordable telescope can you suggest any
for beginners ah I don't have a
telescope myself I've as a kid I always
wanted to have one but I I ended up
never owning a telescope so I would not
be able to suggest one but what I would
recommend is go to any online um uh
website like what you Amazon flip cart
whatever and look up what they
have and uh look at the ratings it
should be four four star plus and
whatever price range you have in mind
you can look for it in that and as long
as you have a reasonable reasonable
amount of ratings and they're all above
four stars it should be a pretty good
telescope and then you can look at
reviews of the telescope in other
websites maybe on websites from other
countries and all so that you get a
better idea that's how I would do it if
I were to if I was in the market for a
telescope right now
so yeah I'm glad that you're interested
in astronomy or whatever it is
telescopes can use for multiple purposes
but I'm assuming astronomy so yeah all
the best do get get a good
one
okay right let's see what else lots of
other questions have I seen Breaking Bad
have I watched Breaking Bad Breaking Bad
fantastic
yeah uh
um yeah it's it's a great series one of
the one of the greatest I've seen so
yeah I've watched it I see a camera
behind you are you a photographer I'm
not a photographer I'm videographer I
make videos right I make videos I have
YouTube channel I have videos there's a
camera here this is an old camera it's a
camera I bought in the year 2002 it's
not a DSLR it's a SLR it is obsolute I
I've just kept it as a display piece and
there's a lens this is a Canon EOS Rebel
from 2002 it still has film in it Kodak
film I believe so I no longer use it but
it's it's there so I thought just keep
it somewhere so it's sitting up there I
have a whole other bunch of cameras in
other places so I'm not a
photographer uh never had the time for
photography I have some good cameras but
I use them for video purposes so
yeah um
okay sahil MRA says I'm from Siliguri
and do you think China will try and
exploit the situation in Bengal and put
pressure on the Siliguri Corridor I
think it's unlikely right now as of now
as of right now that China will uh try
to uh exploit whatever is happening
wherever and put pressure on the silor
corridor right now it is not in China's
interest to to make things worse with
India right now India and China are both
under tremendous amount of pressure from
the
US so I would say it did it is not in
China's interest to to do all that at at
this point in time
okay
um what
else okay Vin Paul Gil says do you
believe India has been Its Own Worst
Enemy since Independence you talk at
length about the Magnificent Mr Neu do
you think Indians or foreign is out to
blame okay I'll tell you what happened
in 1947 there was a transfer of power
India was given dominan status in 1950
or something it became we became a
republic okay there was a transfer of
power from one set of crooks to another
set of crooks
essentially from a set of white skinn
Crooks to a set of brown skinn Crooks
they minions their puppets their
chosen successors
it was not a democratic process by any
means okay and those people who the
British gave power to continued British
policies and that's why India is where
the where India is so I would not blame
the people of
India that people of India have not been
their worst enemies it is those people
who were placed in power by the British
for their own selfish reasons who were
India's worst enemies
essentially okay and you can see the
policies that they implemented for
decades that ruined India that that
artificially hampered India's growth in
progress so you know I don't blame the
people of India at all India has a is a
tremendously great nation with
tremendous potential but the individuals
who have created the system and who are
part of the system most of them are to
blame not all there are some good people
there also lots of good people there
also but the majority have been
mediocre at best I'd say that's why
India is where it
is all
right hi says how to deal with nervous
breakdown I'm just 18 all my all friends
just left alone
well you got to find somebody to trust
maybe family hopefully you can trust
family usually family at least close
family you should be able to trust uh if
you're reasonably lucky otherwise if you
are
like if you really have no one to trust
you got to trust yourself you got to
find a way out of a situation so you've
got to uh invest in
yourself one of the best ways to deal
with depression nervous B on whatever is
to go out and absorb some sunlight it's
impossible to feel depressed when you
have the sun staring you in the face so
you've got to take some time out like
I've said before take some time out be
in the sun absorb some sunlight for a
for a few hours don't worry about skin
damage or whatever go out in
nature and and try to reconnect with
yourself and find your purpose in life
and as long as you are a valuable person
and you make your you transform yourself
into a valuable person you will attract
the right people and you will have
better
friends so you know many people are born
in places where they don't
belong and it it it takes a lot of
willpower and and effort to extricate
yourself out of that place and the
situation and go somewhere better but
once you do that you will attract the
right people around you so it's all
about believing in yourself and
investing in yourself
and overall trusting
yourself and one of the best ways of
doing it you know if you feel down if
you feel low I think you should just go
and exercise work out lift heavy weights
you do it for a few weeks you feel so
much stronger physically and that makes
you stronger mentally there are many
ways of dealing with this the main thing
is don't give up on yourself don't pity
yourself don't indulgent self pity work
on yourself invest in yourself and work
as hard as you possibly can humanly can
can to extricate yourself out of
whichever situation you are in and you
will find that you do have the strength
and the ability to do that so all the
best sir always be positive
never have a negative mindset even
though things may seem bad I know it's
easier said than done but trust me I I
have been
through things okay these things
everybody has at a certain age has been
through all these phases so all the best
I I wish you the best you'll do well
you will do well all right so uh with
that I will end this session we are
again way past two hours so okay this is
the end of today's session so thank you
so much once again for all the questions
I today was able to take many live chat
questions as well so thank you and I
will see you all very soon in the live
streams that will come up next week
until then as always take care and keep
raising your standards and keep on
striving and working hard and keep
asking questions thank you bye